<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sports on Tobias Berger</title>
    <link>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/tags/sports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sports on Tobias Berger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 01:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/tags/sports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Soccer Strategy and Tactics Visually Using StatsBomb Data</title>
      <link>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-4-visualizing-soccer-strategy-and-tactics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 01:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-4-visualizing-soccer-strategy-and-tactics/</guid>
      <description>In this little project, I was messing around with StatsBomb soccer data. I imagined myself being part of the German Women&amp;rsquo;s national team staff, analyzing the English team right before their finals game in the European Championship 2022.
After finishing my PhD analyzing the NBA, I wanted to look at the sport I played as a teenager again, to see what the data and analytics landscape looks like. So keep this in mind, when reading my thoughts and checking my plots here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elo Rating System for Soccer</title>
      <link>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-3-elo-soccer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-3-elo-soccer/</guid>
      <description>An Elo Rating, or simply Elo, is a rating system used to measure the relative skill levels of players or teams in games and sports. It was originally developed for chess by Arpad Elo but has been widely adopted in various sports, including soccer. The Elo rating system provides a numerical representation of a player&amp;rsquo;s or team&amp;rsquo;s skill, making it easier to compare and rank them. In soccer, Elo ratings can be applied to both club teams and national teams, offering a standardized way to evaluate and rank their performances.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
