<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Tobias Berger</title>
    <link>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Tobias Berger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing and Visualizing Data of a Micro Credit Platform</title>
      <link>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-5-kiva-micro-credits-data-analysis-and-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 02:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-5-kiva-micro-credits-data-analysis-and-visualization/</guid>
      <description>Kiva.org is a non-profit organization that operates an online platform to facilitate micro-lending to individuals and small businesses mostly in the global south. The platform connects individual lenders with entrepreneurs and borrowers who need financial assistance to start or expand their businesses, access education, or improve their living conditions.
In a recent project I got to work with some data of this organization. It was quite interesting to dive a little deeper into this field of micro credits and look at some underlying dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Soccer Strategy and Tactics Visually Using StatsBomb Data</title>
      <link>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-4-visualizing-soccer-strategy-and-tactics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 01:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-4-visualizing-soccer-strategy-and-tactics/</guid>
      <description>In this little project, I was messing around with StatsBomb soccer data. I imagined myself being part of the German Women&amp;rsquo;s national team staff, analyzing the English team right before their finals game in the European Championship 2022.
After finishing my PhD analyzing the NBA, I wanted to look at the sport I played as a teenager again, to see what the data and analytics landscape looks like. So keep this in mind, when reading my thoughts and checking my plots here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elo Rating System for Soccer</title>
      <link>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-3-elo-soccer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-3-elo-soccer/</guid>
      <description>An Elo Rating, or simply Elo, is a rating system used to measure the relative skill levels of players or teams in games and sports. It was originally developed for chess by Arpad Elo but has been widely adopted in various sports, including soccer. The Elo rating system provides a numerical representation of a player&amp;rsquo;s or team&amp;rsquo;s skill, making it easier to compare and rank them. In soccer, Elo ratings can be applied to both club teams and national teams, offering a standardized way to evaluate and rank their performances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Radiohead Project - Sentiment Analysis and Music</title>
      <link>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-2-radiohead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-2-radiohead/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered this interesting data set , containing all studio album songs of one of my favorite bands of all time - Radiohead. I checked out how the band has progressed over time looking at their 9 studio albums. This meant examining hard facts like song durations and temporal profiles of their records. However I also analyzed softer dimensions like valence, lyrical density and sadness of the words sung.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesday Contributions - Overview</title>
      <link>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-1-tidytuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-1-tidytuesday/</guid>
      <description>TidyTuesday is a weekly social data project. It provides interesting data regularly and invites you to engage with it. I participate regularly, using Python and Jupyter Notebook, to test out new data science techniques, libraries or plots. All my analyses and visualizations of TidyTuesday datasets are posted here - code and results. The topic range is huge, from climate data to mountain climbers. Link to GitHub Repository
Global Surface Temperature Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
