<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Climate on Tobias Berger</title>
    <link>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/tags/climate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Climate on Tobias Berger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 02:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/tags/climate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Land Use and Land Cover Classification using Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-6-satelite-image-classification-with-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 02:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-6-satelite-image-classification-with-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>In this project I got to work with a fun dataset. The Sentinel-2 satellite images are openly and freely accessible provided in the Earth observation program Copernicus. A group of researchers put some of them together to create novel dataset consisting out of 10 classes with in total 27,000 labeled and geo-referenced images. I used a deep learning approach, utilizing the RESNET50 architecture, to find an algorithm to classify the land use and land cover of the 64x64 pixel pictures as accurate as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyTuesday: Global Surface Temperature</title>
      <link>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-1.1-tidytuesday_global-surface-temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tobiasbergerdata.github.io/Tobias_Portfolio/post/project-1.1-tidytuesday_global-surface-temperature/</guid>
      <description>The data this week comes from the NASA GISS Surface Temperature Analysis (GISTEMP v4). This datasets are tables of global and hemispheric monthly means and zonal annual means. They combine land-surface, air and sea-surface water temperature anomalies (Land-Ocean Temperature Index, L-OTI). The values in the tables are deviations from the corresponding 1951-1980 means.
I created a plot and added the code here.
Link to GitHub Repository
Global Surface Temperature Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
